<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Musings on Design </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://paigebennett.com/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 21:13:11 PST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 21:13:11 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;I&#39;d love to hear from you!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;form action=&#34;https://getsimpleform.com/messages?form_api_token=b31f239fea056c89596a288c31b1a94d&#34; method=&#34;post&#34;&gt;
  First Name: &lt;input type=&#39;text&#39; name=&#39;first_name&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  Last Name: &lt;input type=&#39;text&#39; name=&#39;last_name&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  Email Address: &lt;input type=&#39;text&#39; name=&#39;email_address&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  Message: &lt;textarea name=&#39;message&#39; rows=8&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  &lt;/br&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#39;hidden&#39; name=&#39;redirect_to&#39; value=&#39;http://www.paigebennett.com/contact-thanks/&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#39;submit&#39; value=&#39;Submit&#39; /&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Thanks</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/contact-thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 21:13:11 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/contact-thanks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;I&#39;ll be in touch.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest: Persona to Prototype</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/blog/pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 17:55:14 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/blog/pinterest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pinterest.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; is a website and mobile app that allows users to create visual bookmarks of everything ranging from meals to wedding inspiration to home decor. After launching in the first prototype in 2010, Pinterest has become so popular that &amp;ldquo;pinning&amp;rdquo; something is now woven into modern lexicon. But sometimes it can be hard to filter through pins on your main feed and find content that you&amp;rsquo;re truly interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You currate your main feed by following pinners you like. Currently, there is no way to currate your main feed further by searching and displaying a certain cateogory from the pins of people you follow. Instead, Pinterest pulls in all pins from their entire network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, you cannot filter your main feed to display only home decor-related pins from your pinners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a solution, I created a filter feature that allows you to filter your main feed by category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a better idea, here&amp;rsquo;s a video of the prototype I created.
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;420&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/o3G0VbCgDjo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the filter button is to display content within a set of specific criteria. This feature will shape the content you see into pins that are most helpful to you. Say you are looking for inspiration for home decor. You may now find inspiration faster because your main feed has become more dynamic and impactful through being able to filter the pins you are seeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to create this feature, I first began with a persona: hard-working mom Alee. She&amp;rsquo;s a busy stay-at-home mom with an 8 month old baby and is redecorating her home room by room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alee loves DIY projects and turns to Pinterest for inspiration. She curates the content on her Pinterest feed by following &amp;ldquo;pinners&amp;rdquo; that reflect a similar style as Alee&amp;rsquo;s. Even so, her main feed is a mixture of pins ranging from various categories. This is not always helpful, especially when Alee scrolls through her main feed while on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alee wants to be able to see specific categories of pins that pinners she follows have shared. With this function, Alee can take her curated content and curate it further, creating a main feed that features only those categories she&amp;rsquo;s interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/images/AleePersona.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;image-1&#34; data-title=&#34;Alee Persona&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/AleePersona.jpg&#34;/img&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After rounding out my persona to include richer behavioral and needs insights, I created the design stories and task flows. This influenced the wire frames and prototype that I was then able to create. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at these different components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design Stories&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature will allow Alee to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;filter her feed by category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;select a category to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;view her main feed based on a preset category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add a filter to her feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove a filter from her feed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find a pin based on her category preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(and with much more ease), &amp;ldquo;Heart&amp;rdquo; and/or &amp;ldquo;Pin&amp;rdquo; a pin she likes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Task Flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alee&amp;rsquo;s motive for using Pinterest is to reference pins she likes. I decided that she would most likely either &amp;ldquo;heart&amp;rdquo; a pin or &amp;ldquo;pin&amp;rdquo; a pin to one of her DIY boards. Thus, my task flow shows her journey with Pinterest ending in either of these two actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Pinterest%20Task%20Flow.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Sketches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/WireFrames.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned during this part of the process was that the categories needed to be a pop up box, as opposed to a separate window. Sketching out 6 different ways to display categories helped clarify that this was the more effective route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wireframes (and a few fun surprises)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating my wireframes, I did a short usability study with a few people and noticed something immediately: the filter button was confusing.
I had used the filter icon that&amp;rsquo;s part of Andriod design convention. However, the feedback I received was that users thought the button was meant to sort content&amp;hellip;.not choose a category. Uh oh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/FilterExample.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought to use the same categories icon that Pinterest has on its site. However, this icon on mobile can be confusing. After looking at how other Andriod apps displayed their filter button, I used Fitmob as inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/FitmobExample.png&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s simple and direct. There&amp;rsquo;s no doubting what this button does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wireframes will help explain:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Wireframes 1.jpg&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Wireframes 2.jpg&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Wireframes 3.jpg&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Wireframes 4.jpg&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; width=&#34;500&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prototype&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My prototype will help give you a taste at how this feature would work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;420&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/o3G0VbCgDjo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of how this feature might look on the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/HighFidelity.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learnings &amp;amp; Next Steps&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I worked through the process of creating this feature, I learned that the most obvious answer isn&amp;rsquo;t always the best one (see the filter icon dilemma above). Like &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jjg/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jesse James Garrett&lt;/a&gt; cautions in his book &lt;em&gt;The Elements of User Experience&lt;/em&gt;, my filter feature does create a few edge cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: lets say Alee chooses the Cars &amp;amp; Motorcycles category and none of the pinners she follows have users this category of content. What message would she see? Or while Pinterest has &amp;lsquo;Recent Categories,&amp;rsquo; would it be of value to also include the ability to preset a list of categories?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are both questions that have cropped up &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; of my feature. My next steps would include working through these edge cases and creating the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also not convinced that the current filter button is the best way to represent the button&amp;rsquo;s functionality. There could be other icons that also communicate the intent, while staying in line with the Pinterest look and feel. I would want to explore this further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the filter button helps users curate their content, I believe that there&amp;rsquo;s much more to explore. This one feature only scratched the surface. So stay tuned for more. This story is certainly not over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions or feedback? Reach out to me: &lt;a href=&#34;https://paige@tradecrafted.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;paige@tradecrafted.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do not work for Pinterest. I just love the app and owe most of my homemade dinners to Pinterest inspiration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vint: A Usability Study</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/blog/vint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 19:29:32 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/blog/vint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My wedding is 4 months away, about the time when brides start panicking about things like invitations, caterers and the fit of their wedding dress. Me, I’m more concerned about the last issue&amp;ndash; my wedding dress (and fitting nicely into it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That concern is largely want made new fitness app Vint catch my eye last week. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joinvint.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vint&lt;/a&gt; touts itself as a “peer to peer fitness marketplace.” I was drawn to the app because of the ability to book a personal trainer in my area for less than what I would have to pay for in a gym. Since my exercise choices are largely based on time (early mornings) and location, I was excited about Vint and what it could do to help me reach my wedding fitness goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to be honest, my first few interactions with the app were a bit frustrating. It took me several attempts to find and successfully book a trainer. So in the vein of improvement (and because I want Vint to succeed), I decided to focus a guerrilla usability study on this app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform&lt;/strong&gt;: Android HTC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt;: I use Vint to locate and book personal trainers in my area for early morning training sessions. I’ve had some trouble successfully finding and booking a trainer and wanted to test and see if other people had the same issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users&lt;/strong&gt;: I targeted my local Laundromat (captive audience), my Lyft driver Paul and the nice people at Workshop Café. In total, I interviewed 6 people and recorded my time with them. You can view the videos &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/qxuw8nq9v6cabq9/AACWB_ikpNnqZ83eI9rFUn3Wa?dl=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Cafe.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began by asking them the following filter questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’ve been given $500 for a personal trainer. How would you go about finding one?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you used a personal trainer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you look for in a personal trainer? Tell me about price, type and location.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was the process of finding a personal trainer process like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you haven’t used a personal trainer, are you interested in getting one?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell me about why you haven’t used a personal trainer before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tasks&lt;/strong&gt;: I then asked users to complete 4 common tasks that I do most often within the app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find an instructor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book a session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Request a new session time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancel a session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;: While every user experienced some specific difficulty with the app, there were 3 pain points that stood out as causing users the most frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Painpoints.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pain Point #1: Canceling a Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I don’t know, I really don’t know.” –Paul&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pain point that I am intimately familiar with. The first time I used Vint, I accidentally booked a session and could not find how to cancel it. As I found from talking to users, I am not the only one who had trouble with this task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cancel a session, you must visit your profile page to view and cancel your bookings. Two of the users gave up during this task, not ever making it to the profile page. They shared with me that they would have contacted the trainer directly to cancel. Two other users who gave up on the task said that it was &amp;ldquo;just not possible to cancel a session.&amp;rdquo; Only one user was able to find and cancel a session without visiting other pages first in search of their booking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’d rather something be in this first page than have to go back to my profile.” –Lisa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;: One of my users referenced what she called her favorite app- Urban Sitter. She said she would have liked to see Vint display recent bookings (with a cancel option) on the main page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Urban Sitter as my inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/baby.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Cancel2.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(One fun bug we found was with the booking procces itself. After booking, error message would pop up saying that the booking was not successful. This caused users to try a second time, which produced no error message. Even though they received an error message, the first booking had gone through, which means users were stuck with two bookings. I&amp;rsquo;ve contacted Vint and they&amp;rsquo;ve since fixed the bug.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pain Point #2: Hard to notice categorization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s not giving me a lot of information.” –Oscar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of the users I spoke with noticed the exercise categories, dates and times at the bottom of each instructors picture on the main page. Three users remarked how they wished there were categories but none noticed the categorization that was present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Category2.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pain Point #3: Confusing Function of the Vint Logo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I think this app is very poorly designed.” –Lisa&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users would click on the Vint logo expecting it to take them back a page. Instead, the logo took them to the main page. Once in the main page, clicking on the logo would exit users out of the app. Get rid of the Vint logo after the homepage. It’s not needed because you know what app you are in. Instead, include the back arrow to show users how to go back in a page. (leaning on material design). They couldn’t see the back button because the logo asset is too big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you compare the Vint logo to another app&amp;rsquo;s logo (in this case, Gmail), you can see that the Vint logo is larger. This might have added to the difficulty users had in noticing the back arrow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/gmail.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize that Vint&amp;rsquo;s design is in keeping with Andriod&amp;rsquo;s design principles but the logo isn&amp;rsquo;t needed- users know what app they&amp;rsquo;re in. Instead, I am leaning on material design and recommending that they remove the logo and increase the size of the back arrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Backbutton.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is similar to Airbnb&amp;rsquo;s app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Airbnb.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that when you click on the Vint logo while on the main page, it will exit you out of the app. This happened to every user I interviewed and their reaction was a mixture of surprise, confusion and dismay.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving Forward&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several other recommendations that I will be addressing in the near future. Like&amp;hellip;.onboarding! This wasn&amp;rsquo;t something I could complete within a short timeframe but designing an onboarding experience would solve several problems I noticed, including cancelation, confusing profiles and unclear categorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like how Pinterest does onboarding and recommend that Vint create a similar experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Pinterest%201.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Pinterest%204.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This design is also a little less intensive to create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stay tuned for Vint: Part deux (and updates on how that wedding dress fits).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I do not work for Vint and am not affiliated with them in any way. I do use the app and am passionate about providing delightful user experiences.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/portfolio/pinterest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 12:07:32 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/portfolio/pinterest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vint</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/portfolio/vint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 12:07:32 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/portfolio/vint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elements of User Experience</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/blog/third/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 16:17:54 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/blog/third/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In some ways, Jesse James Garrett introduced me into the (official) world of User Experience.
His book, the &lt;em&gt;Elements of User Experience&lt;/em&gt;, was the first work on UX that I read. As such, I appreciated the simple, clear and relatable language that Garrett used to introduce newbies like me to the UX world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garrett described user experience as “the experience the product creates for the people who use it in the real world.” Sometimes we have great experiences with products (I’m looking at you, nostalgic Timehop), other times the experience is frustrating (like anytime I try to navigate Netflix on my tv). Our jobs as designers are to make that experience one of joy, delight and ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are many things that Garrett’s book helped me understand better, I’ll share with you my top highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Five Planes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garrett describes the five planes as layers that build upon one another and influence how a site looks and behaves. His five planes are: Surface, Skeleton, Structure, Scope and Strategy. What I loved about this is how it broke down a site into the many, many different facets, from abstract (strategy) to concrete (surface). Garrett emphasized the importance of each plane’s dependence on the other. For example, if you miss getting the strategy right, it will affect the scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Plane Approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While each plane is dependent on one another, that doesn’t mean that you have to finish each plane before you can start work on the next section. That could lead to frustration for everyone involved. Instead, Garrett provided a straight-forward, great piece of advice to keep in mind: “have work on each plane &lt;strong&gt;finish&lt;/strong&gt; before work on the next can finish.” I appreciated this clarification because I have been a part of teams before that have tried to finish one plane before starting another. It did lead to frustration- both from the team and our users. Had we taken Garrett’s advice, perhaps we would have all been better off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Understand the consequences of your solution to the problem.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was one of the most influential statements that Garrett made and I hope that it’s one I will always keep top of mind. Sometimes we can be so focused on fixing the problem that we don’t take a step back to consider how that solution could possibly cause a ripple effect throughout the design. It takes your team thinking about each plane to avoid this. Garrett provided this helpful diagram to show what this might look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/third_diagram.png&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Diagram&lt;/h4&gt;
        
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you approach your product development process with the complete user experience in mind, you can come out of it with a product that’s an asset, not a liability.” Yes, Mr. Garrett. Yes indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First User Study (The Shaky, Grass Roots Edition) </title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/blog/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:58:43 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/blog/second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I’m most excited about at Tradecraft is getting the opportunity to study and implement user studies following the lean startup philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Laura Klein’s book UX for Lean Startups, “Lean UX is solidly data driven.” In other words, you test first, assume never.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should set the stage now and share with you that up to this point, my experience with user studies have been purely grassroots. Really grassroots. But, since my goal for this blog is to be one that highlights (hopefully) progress, let me introduce you to User Study #1: The Grassroots Edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right off the bat, I can tell you how we wrongly went about this study: we didn’t first form a hypothesis that we were trying to answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what we assumed: our website messaging wasn’t clear, the website flow made no sense and our checkout system was confusing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically we went into the user study looking for validation for what we wanted to do, which was completely rework the website and messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined the startup after the website had launched but I wished this study had been done prior to launching the site. Again, that’s where the lean startup school of thought makes so much sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started by interviewing 16 people, all non-users of our product. With the exception of 4, they had never heard of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had them walk through our booking process, from the homepage to choosing a product they were interested in, booking and reserving that product. Finally, we asked them about a couple of specific pages we felt were lacking in clarity and flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“$60 is too much. What am I getting for that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Validation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user study validated a lot of what we already knew, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Messaging: It wasn’t clear to the user what exactly we were offering or where they could have the meal. Would the chef come to their house? Was it at the chef’s house? Was it delivery? The user really didn’t know.
Dynamic Pricing: The need for pricing that changed depending on how many people you have at a dinner. The price displayed isn’t what you would pay if there was only 2 people&amp;hellip;or a larger group like 15. Users were unaware that booking a dinner under the minimum number of people shown would result in a higher price per person.
Flow: From the homepage to the meals page, filtering down to what you wanted to see (cooking classes, meals, tours) wasn’t intuitive. Part of that stemmed from hazy messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I thought you served only Italian food.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Insights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also got a lot of great feedback on issues we didn’t know were issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consistent Images: One thing we heard was about our H1 image on our homepage. It conveyed (to a couple of users) that we offered one genre of food. Of course, there’s no way a picture of food will convey every genre but still, this was interesting feedback. If only to reiterate how important visuals are to our site.
Menu Clarity: We have pictures of food and a menu listed on the meals page but you’ll notice they’re not listed side-by-side. We heard from some users that this added to their confusion, especially when the menu featured food they were unfamiliar with.
Social Trust: We offer Facebook login but not using the Facebook symbol (it simply says “Login”). The study showed us that users wanted to see the Facebook symbol. To them, it added validity and trust.
Next Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The raw feedback was enlightening enough but when it came to actionable items to provide backend, we focused on three areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Messaging on the home and meals pages&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dynamic pricing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;How it Works&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Our reasoning for putting How it Works as a high priority was because of heavy site traffic to that page.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would love to share the before and after images but my path took a quick turn while in the middle of this study. Instead, I handed it over to my very capable coworkers and look forward to seeing the end result as a user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Journey From Journalism to Design</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/blog/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 13:42:29 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/blog/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the days before iPhones and internet, while other kids were playing teacher or house, I was reading the newspaper into a tape recorder, “anchoring” my own tv news show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the time I was young, I knew what I wanted to be when I grew up. It never wavered or changed, like other things in my life (such as that dark period before I loved avocados or when I hated wine), I never second guessed this dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter college. No major change, no shift, no worries. Print journalism was dying and I was told that the probability of anchoring in a large market was small. Still, that didn’t deter me. There was something about communication- pure and simple with your audience- that was innate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things changed and sands shifted. Like many journalists, the allure of PR drew me in. It was a semi-regular schedule, semi-regular hours and more pay that my measly producer salary drew. And though I didn’t love it, it taught me well. Through PR, I was introduced to tech. I was still a storyteller and (in theory) the audience was still my main priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found, though, that I increasingly wanted to connect with a brand’s audience in a deeper way- to help build the trust and customer experience. Essentially, I wanted to manage the community. And so, earlier this summer, I jumped at a chance to direct the community for an early stage startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was lean&amp;hellip;.incredibly so. But almost immediately after accepting, my role shifted completely. And while that’s to be expected to a certain point in the startup world, it became something that I didn’t recognize for a vision I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. But nonetheless, there were opportunities to learn everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were building everything on our own. The messaging, the voice, the experience. It was all on us. And these things I loved. I loved conducting a grassroots study to figure out how people perceive us and our website. I loved figuring out what people liked and what they hated and why. I don’t think I realized I was doing user experience. But what I realized is that I really, really liked it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so a few weeks ago, when I received word that funding wasn’t going as expected and that wasn’t any money to pay me…well, I guess you could say that it was my first taste of the not so glamorous world of startups. They’re not all the 1% success stories. Some crash and burn. And while it hurts, it can also be a chance for a new chapter (&amp;ldquo;One door closes&amp;rdquo; and all that jazz….).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So on November 24th, I began a new journey, studying UX at Tradecraft, under the visionary Kate Rutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, my childhood passion has come full circle. When I was a journalist, the audience was my main focus. It mattered most that I understood my audience and how to communicate with them.  In critical times, if I did not understand them, I would fail  as a communicator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audience- the user- will continue to be my main focus. I have a lot to learn but between you and me, I haven’t been this excited since I was a kid, reading articles from the Picayune Item into my tape recorder. So raise your glass with me. Here&amp;rsquo;s to a new journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://paigebennett.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 12:55:29 PST</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://paigebennett.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure &gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;/images/Paige.jpg&#34;  /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Southerner meets San Francisco. I began my career in a newsroom, made a home in Oman and Austin along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the written word and figuring out the &amp;lsquo;why?&amp;rsquo; in things.  I&amp;rsquo;m learning to code and build this site piece by piece. Welcome to my journey into UX design. Pull up a chair and I&amp;rsquo;ll pour you a drink.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>